TANVIR HASAN

House 10, Road 05, Kamarpara, Uttara • Dhaka, Bangladesh

Contact: +8801706986905 Email: tanvir.cse@iubat.edu

LinkedIn:

www.linkedin.com/in/tanvir-hasan98

GitHub: https://github.com



OBJECTIVE

Desiring an opportunity as a research assistant where I can employ my hard-work, organizational skills, attention to details, keen sight, thirst for knowledge, technological and analytical skills to support a team of researchers while broadening my knowledge with new insights, information and experiences.

EDUCATION

International University of Business Agriculture and Technology (Dhaka, Bangladesh)

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering;

Jan 2018 – Jan 2022

CGPA: 3.78 out of 4.00

Ideal College (Dhanmondi, Dhaka)

Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC), Science Background

Jul 2014 – Aug 2016

GPA: 5.00 Out of 5.00

Sondail High School (Nangalkot, Cumilla)

Secondary School Certificate (SSC), Science Background

Jan 2012 – May 2014

GPA: 4.50 Out of 5.00

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

International University of Business Agriculture and Technology (Dhaka, Bangladesh)

Lecturer, Department of Computer Science and Engineering

Jan 2023 – Present

Taken Classes of various courses of different levels.

Prepared lesson plans, grading papers, grade-sheets.

Taken consultation classes for providing additional support to weak students.

Supervised 16 students who are in their final year internship.

INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE

Implevista BD

Jr. Software Engineer

Jan 2022 - Dec 2022

Working with ASP .Net core and Angular to develop web application. Using MSSQL Server for database. Also experienced in JavaScript, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, JQuery, ES6 ,Bootstrap5, HTML,CSS, Entity Framework Core. Tested API endpoints using postman.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Bachelor Thesis Jan 2021- Dec 2021

Thesis Title: Bangla character based license plate detection for vehicle.

There was a proposal for a model which was based on CNN for image processing and YOLOv4 for object detection.

Industrial Project

CCULB(Solution for CCULB, Bangladesh)

CCULB- Co-Operative Credit League Bangladesh is mini-banking system where user can perform all kinds of banking activities like create account, money transaction, take loan etc. There are different types of account like share account, savings account, FDR etc.

Tools & Technologies: Angular 13, TypeScript, Asp.Net, C#, Microsoft Dynamics 365 CRM, Microsoft Dataverse Web API, Power Apps, Dataverse REST Builder, XMSSQL.

Activities performed: Involved in client communications, Requirement analysis, Entity Design, Development, Refactoring, Testing, Bug fixing, Enhancing, and Maintenance.

IQUIDI (Solution for Implevista BD LTD, Bangladesh)

IQUIDI- is an accounting software where organization can keep all record like procurement management, inventory management, sales and invoice management, manufacturing system, Document management, manage budget, record all transaction,

manage budget etc.

Tools & Technologies: Angular 13, TypeScript, Asp.Net, C#, Microsoft Dynamics 365 CRM, Redux, RESTful APIs, HDFC Payment Gateway, MSSQL.

Activities performed: Involved in client communications, Requirement analysis, Development, Refactoring, Testing, Bug fixing, Enhancing, and Maintenance

HONORS AND AWARDS

- Honorable Mention at IUBAT Intra University Programming Contest 2020
- Honorable Mention at IUBAT Intra University Programming Contest 2021

TRAININGS

Training on Outcome Based Education (OBE)

Two days long OBE Training by Department of CSE

2nd and 3rd Sep 2023

Training on Course Outcome/Program Outcome attainment based on Rubrics.

Training on Complex Engineering Problems and Knowledge Profile Activities.

Complete Web Development Course(ASP .Net Core)

Three Months long Web Development from online platforms.

Completed: ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Web API, ASP.NET Razor Pages, ASP.NET Web Forms, Blazor, Entity Framework , Entity Framework (EF),ASP.NET Scaffolding and MSSQL.

Complete Web Development Course with Jhankar Mahbub

Five Months long Web Development Course by Programming Hero

Completed: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Tailwind, JavaScript, TypeScript, DOM, ES6, JSON, API, Chrome Devtool, React, Express, Node, MongoDB, Firebase Authentication, Payment Gateway etc.

COMPETITION AND SUMMIT PARTICIPATIONS

Conference on Robotics, IoT and Machine learning in 21st Century

IUBAT University 21-22 Sep 2019

Two days of the conference were organized about Robotics, IOT, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, and the scope of research and innovation in this domain.

Google Cloud Study Jam 2019

Independent University Bangladesh (IUB)

28 June, 2019

A day-long workshop where I learned about Data storing, cloud computing, Machine Language, and Artificial Intelligence.

IUBAT Intra University Programming Contest 2020& 2021 in IUBAT

IUBAT CSE Department arrange Programming Contest Every year to motivate and practice programming.

INTERESTED RESEARCH AREA

Machine learning, Artificial Intelligent and Computer Vision, Software Engineering.

OTHER INFORMATIONS

Language Skill: Bangla (Native), Proficiency in English (IELTS 6.5)

Hobbies: Travelling, Exploring New Technology, Playing Cricket,

football, badminton etc.

REFERENCES

Prof Dr. Utpal Kanti Das

Professor & Chair,

Department of Computer Science and
Engineering, IUBAT

Contact No: +8801819199419

Email: ukd@iubat.edu

Rashedul Islam

Assistant Professor & Coordinator, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, IUBAT Contact No: +8801776445218

Email: rashed@iubat.edu